Three.
Ignition.
Liftoff.
Exploring the universe is humanity's oldest dream.
If satellites are the cattle and sheep we graze,
then the universe is our pasture.
I'm Wu Wei,
a star grazer at the China Aerospace Flight Control Center.
This is our story.
The competition is about to begin.
Please enter in an orderly manner with your tickets.
Wake up.
The competition is starting soon.
Come take a look.
The machine stopped spinning again. Hurry.
Look.
The dog's wheel won't spin.
The drive system keeps reporting errors.
Bro, think of something.
Think of something.
Wei,
think of a way.
Don't you want to impress the flight control leaders?
That's Qin Bojun.
Qin Bojun!
Your interview success depends on this.
Flight control.
He might really be my interviewer.
Then hurry up, bro.
The competition is starting soon.
If we take home a 3rd consecutive championship,
your interview will be a breeze.
A breeze.
Let me eat a bite first.
Let me think.
Take out the spare part.
Why is there another robot here?
Whose is this? Which team?
Doesn't matter which team.
Must be rich kids.
Looks like they spent a lot.
Rich or not,
they're just here for the ride, you know?
Buying such good parts is useless.
We are definitely first.
Let me see.
It has so many random modules.
So flashy.
Just a vase, is it useful?
Pay-to-win players. I hate this kind the most.
Who are you? Don't touch that.
He pushed me.
Who are you?
This is our Polytech Team lounge.
This is our Hangda lounge.
Did you see the big letters on the door?
Wrong room. Sorry.
So awkward.
Let's go.
Go.
Wait.
It suddenly won't turn on.
What did you just touch?
Did you touch it?
No.
He didn't touch it.
Did you?
No.
He didn't touch it, and neither did I.
Impossible.
I just checked it before leaving.
Why is it suddenly reporting an error?
You don't like being called a vase,
but you don't even understand your own stuff.
And you ask me?
Stop playing dumb.
It means you are setting us up.
Forget it. Let them go.
Look.
Your teammate knows what it means.
Take your scrap metal and get out.
Who are you calling scrap metal?
Not necessary.
They can't mess with my stuff.
You wouldn't understand.
Who cares what it means.
Let's go.
Pay-to-win player. Trash.
What did you say?
Just go.
So stupid.
I should have talked back to them.
What wouldn't we understand?
Who didn't understand?
Your parts are just a little more expensive.
A hero's origin doesn't matter.
He's the one who doesn't understand.
What does he mean exactly?
Wei.
Wei, calm down.
So energetic.
Calm down.
It's too late to react now.
We lost the argument, but we'll win on the field.
Brother, check where the robot is broken.
I checked.
Ours is a brushed motor.
It short-circuited and burnt out.
I told you to get the spare one.
I didn't buy it.
Brother.
We only have a little fund left.
We bought self-heating hot pot with all of it.
And I didn't even get a bite.
You two ate it all.
You shouldn't eat it either.
No problem.
Was the joystick not connected just now?
You scared me.
I thought they really messed with it.
When will you give me the prize money?
The match hasn't started. What prize money?
Let's win first.
We will definitely win.
Try it.
Is there any problem?
No problem.
I rented an apartment.
If I don't pay the rent today,
they won't keep it for me.
I think
even if we win the game and get the prize money,
you probably won't be able to rent that apartment.
Are you really not going to pursue a Ph.D.?
It's an exemption from the exam, bro.
It's a pity to give it up.
I'm tired of studying.
You haven't discussed it with your family, have you?
Mrs. Chen Bing will hit the roof if she knows.
Just leave it.
Okay, this is it.
Pick a good one from the rotten ones.
Find me a zip tie.
The size of this old-fashioned gasket is wrong.
It needs to be fixed.
Zip tie.
Brother, we only have this.
Okay, there are rough ways to play.
I have to make something out of it today.
Let Qin Bojun see.
Then it will be easy to get into Flight Control.
Son.
Where are you?
Your dad and I have arrived at the school.
Dad.
Did you tell my mom or not?
My son is the most handsome.
Ying Ziqi.
No.
I did.
But you might need to tell her again yourself.
What are you doing?
Ziqi's speech is coming up soon.
Hurry up.
Mrs. Chen.
Why don't you go ahead?
I need to go to the restroom.
You're always stalling.
Hurry up. Let's go.
Mr. Qiao.
Hello, Mr. Qiao.
Mrs. Chen, what brings you here?
Of course I'd come to Ziqi's graduation.
Doesn't he have a speech?
Our Ziqi...
For all the major events in his life,
I have to be present.
You... you don't know?
Know what?
After Ying Ziqi finished his graduation procedures,
he already left school.
Left school?
Then where did he go?
He said he doesn't plan to pursue a Ph.D.
And his recommendation quota for postgraduate studies...
he gave that up too.
Mr. Ying knows all about this.
This...
What is he trying to do?
What are you doing?
Why didn't you tell me such a big thing?
Ziqi said he has his own ideas.
He...
Where is Ziqi now?
Call him! Call him now!
I'm calling.
Mrs. Chen!
My friends,
welcome to this year's
Aerospace Cup Robot Combat Competition!
Today we will have our final match.
The Hangda Team will face this competition's dark horse,
the Ligong Team.
Is your big baby fixed?
Yeah, we'll crush you in a bit.
Good parts are useless.
True heroes don't care about origins.
Scrap metal can still strike back.
Strike back?
You've read too many web novels.
See you in the arena.
All right.
Our exciting match is about to begin.
As everyone knows,
previous robot competitions
have provided national aerospace projects
with a large number of outstanding talents.
Today, we are even more honored to invite
the chief designer of the China Aerospace Flight Control Center,
Mr. Qin Bojun.
If the defending champion, the Hangda Team,
can win this competition today,
they will break the competition record
and become the first ever to win three consecutive championships.
All right.
First to appear is the born champion,
Jedi.
Weighing 13.6 kilograms,
and with a two-wheel drive.
It is equipped with a 20-millimeter-thick
aluminum alloy armor all around.
Its rotational speed can reach 12,000 RPM.
It is known as the strongest tank in history,
a drum spinner combat robot.
And entering next
is a combat robot that supports
both vertical and offset horizontal spinning modules,
Storm Dog.
The vertical and offset horizontal spinning modules
make Storm Dog's driving force, control,
and even grip
more precise.
A well-deserved strongest warrior.
It's worth mentioning that
the new generation of technologies
you see in this competition
will be applied in the future
to various fields including the aerospace industry.
Okay.
Our match
begins now.
Storm Dog launches the first round of attack
against Jedi.
Although Jedi managed to dodge it,
it still seems a bit flustered.
Storm Dog's large blunt blade
hit Jedi's armor.
What's the use of expensive parts?
Relax.
Jedi's armor
shows no fear despite the impact.
Jedi is hit hard again.
How will it respond?
It's just for show.
Storm Dog has always dominated the arena with strong attacks,
but Jedi happens to be a robot
that excels in defense.
This is destined to be
a wonderful duel between spear and shield.
It dodged!
Jedi actually dodged
Storm Dog's impact.
Why dodge?
Think of something, bro.
Don't you want the prize money?
Let me do it.
They swapped drivers.
Swapping won't help.
I'll teach him a lesson.
It's a brushed motor.
Jedi's brushed motor,
paired with the two-wheel drive system,
exerts the advantage of low speed and high torque,
dodging Storm Dog's savage impact.
Beautiful!
A thrust back!
What a pity. Storm Dog is bounced off.
Jedi is unstoppable. Amazing!
Jedi once again dodged
Storm Dog's attack.
Now Storm Dog
has been pursuing Jedi.
All right.
We see that Jedi has changed its tactics.
It uses its agility advantage
to keep avoiding
direct frontal conflict with Storm Dog.
Does Jedi have any
ultimate moves we don't know about?
What exactly is it brewing?
How will Storm Dog deal with Jedi?
What kind of surprise will it bring us?
Now.
Storm Doggo reveals its sword.
What happened? What happened?
Storm Doggo crashed into the wall!
Jedi Knight uses its advantage
to catch the enemy in a trap.
Right now,
Jedi Knight has activated its taunt.
It's stuck.
Storm Doggo's giant blunt sword
just took a hit,
and it's stuck.
Obviously, Jedi Knight
noticed Storm Doggo's problem.
Will Jedi Knight
be able to seize this opportunity?
The chance is here.
Jedi Knight is about to launch a fatal blow.
Storm Doggo, watch out!
Dodge it!
Wait a bit more.
Jedi Knight is making its move.
Jedi Knight is getting closer.
What should Storm Doggo do?
Storm Doggo completes a counterattack!
The most exciting moment of this robotics competition!
Storm Doggo uses its broken
blunt sword and regular sword
to cut through Jedi Knight.
Jedi Knight has completely lost its mobility.
Storm Doggo is the final champion!
Alright, let's take another look
at that thrilling moment just now.
We won.
Wei, we won.
Wei.
Storm Doggo was cornered
but didn't give up.
Instead, it used its dual weapon system
to target Jedi Knight.
Three-peat! Three-peat! Three-peat!
This is all thanks to Storm Doggo's operator,
the Aviation University team's rich experience,
and the power of Storm Doggo's weapon system.
Referee,
the opponent is overweight and broke the rules.
How is that possible?
When we registered and during the group stage,
it weighed 13.9 kilograms every time.
You must have weighed it wrong, referee.
Measure it again.
It's over 14 kilograms.
It's indeed a violation.
According to the rules, we can't declare you the winner.
Jedi Knight weighs 13.6 kilograms.
When the weapon module reaches full speed,
it generates 4,500 joules,
capable of withstanding
an attack from something 0.4 kilograms heavier than itself.
Unless Storm Doggo exceeds this weight...
Wei,
how can it be overweight?
We didn't touch anything.
Zip ties. Zip ties.
Ladies and gentlemen,
an unexpected situation just occurred.
The Aviation University team's robot, Storm Doggo,
exceeded the competition's weight limit.
After discussions between the on-site referees
and the competition committee,
the winner of this final is
the Polytechnic team!
I didn't see a counterattack,
but it's definitely a piece of junk.
I realized you're really asking for it.
Cut the crap. What did you say?
The referee is here.
Wei, don't.
One more time.
I can beat you even though I'm lighter than you. Do you believe it?
Come on,
both of you.
Come on.
I'm asking you. Why are you looking at your phone?
Let's do it again.
I don't have time to play with you.
Do it again.
Don't go.
I'm leaving.
Don't pull me.
Don't forget to take the prize money.
Wei.
Who's playing with you two?
Forget it.
Ying Ziqi.
Mr. Qin, long time no see.
You look stunning today.
I'm almost
blinded.
That's the Ying Ziqi I remember.
How come I heard that you
gave up the Ph.D. recommendation?
Yes.
Then you must have a better choice.
Not yet.
It's been almost a year since your internship ended.
What's your plan?
I...
I have no plan yet.
Mr. Qin, I have an emergency right now.
I have to...
Okay.
Go ahead.
Why are there no windows here?
What do you want to do?
What do I want?
You scammed me out of my third consecutive championship.
And you want to leave?
The match is over.
Go to the referee if you have complaints.
What's there to appeal?
You said it's over.
Where can I appeal?
You can't afford to lose, so you play by the rules?
Rules are rules.
I have no time to play with you.
Don't go anywhere.
If you have the guts, compete with me, Wu Wei,
for one more round.
Are you going or not?
Ziqi.
Driver.
Stop the car. Stop now.
Just tell me if you dare.
Ziqi.
Ziqi, stop right there.
Ziqi, don't run.
Ying Ziqi, stop right there.
Mr. Chen.
Hurry, after him.
Slow down.
Hurry, catch him.
Okay.
Ying Ziqi.
Handsome.
I'm talking to you. Are you going or not?
You're the handsome one.
Bai.
You brought all the luggage over, right?
Okay.
What?
You told my mom?
Mom.
You've grown up, your wings are strong,
and you want to fly solo. Want to make your own decisions, right?
Such a big matter,
why didn't you discuss it with me?
You have a guaranteed Ph.D. spot but refuse to take it.
Are you letting me down?
Are you letting your advisor down?
Are you letting yourself down?
Mrs. Chen.
Are you trying to cover for him?
Acting like this,
you're going to ruin your son.
No, it's not that.
I need to use the restroom,
I really need to pee.
Go.
Son,
tell me,
what are you really thinking?
Give me a reason.
Speak.
Isn't it good to stay at the university as a professor after getting your Ph.D.?
Your grandparents,
even your disappointing dad,
are all Ph.D.s.
I didn't have the conditions to continue studying back then,
but I didn't miss out on
my part-time master's and Ph.D. degrees.
I've been a teacher all my life,
and I can't even educate my own child properly.
Where do I put my face?
There's no room for discussion.
You must study it.
What are you doing?
I wasn't planning on discussing it with you.
Xiao... Xiaoqi! Xiaoqi!
Whatever it is,
go home and talk it over with your mom.
No, look at him!
Why are you stopping me?
Go stop him!
My bag!
Okay.
Slow down.
Xiaoqi, wait for me!
This kid...
Xiaoqi! Xiaoqi!
Xiaoqi!
Slow down.
Come here.
Xiaoqi, come here,
hurry and help out.
Hurry up.
Mrs. Chen, are you okay?
I can't.
Hurry up!
I can't. Mrs. Chen, come.
Slow down.
Quick, sit down.
Here, let me see.
How's your foot?
Does it hurt?
How could it not hurt?
Not only does my leg hurt,
my heart hurts too.
Xiaoqi,
Xiaoqi.
I'm so anxious,
isn't it all for your own good?
From childhood to adulthood,
how many cram schools did I accompany you to?
How many competitions did we attend,
rain or shine?
Parents love their children,
so they plan far ahead for them.
You know that, right?
Xiaoqi,
listen to your dad.
Let's talk about it when we get home.
Do you really want to make your mom mad?
Go home with Mom.
Give me the car keys.
Bring the car here.
Go quickly.
Let's go home.
All right.
Let's not be angry anymore.
Certificate of Honor.
The 12th National Math Olympiad.
The first place goes to
Chen Xiaoyi from Zhongda Primary School.
The second place goes to
Ying Ziqi from Hang Kong Primary School.
Wu Wei, what do you want to show me?
My mom is urging me to go home.
What's the rush?
Ying Ziqi,
hold this for me.
This is a rocket built by your big brother himself.
Isn't it cool?
I'll let you see today
what a rocket is.
Let me demonstrate it for you.
According to Newton's third law,
if you open a hole in a rocket filled with high-pressure gas,
the gas will shoot out,
generating thrust.
When the thrust is greater than the rocket's own gravity,
the rocket takes off.
Today, let your big brother tell you
what the sea of stars is
and what flying freely is.
Oh my god!
Who is it?
I'm out of here.
Don't say you saw me, got it?
Wait for me!
Who?
What are you doing?
Who did this?
Tell me!
I know it wasn't you.
Was it
that boy Wu Wei?
Traitor!
Who did it?
Let's see where you can run!
I didn't expect
you to be a traitor with those thick eyebrows and big eyes.
I'll kill you!
Hit me! Hit me!
Invincible transformation!
Mom.
Who did you fight with this time?
I'm calling your teacher.
No, no, no.
No.
No, Mom.
It was Ying Ziqi from my class.
We were just playing around.
Just a friendly spar.
Friendly spar?
Was it a friendly spar,
or did you provoke him first?
Did you break the glass of the bicycle shed downstairs?
You are getting more and more outrageous.
The glass thing was just an operational error.
Mom,
are you not feeling well again?
Don't be angry. Don't be angry, Mom.
I'll apologize to Grandpa Zhang.
Mom.
It's nothing.
I'm just a little tired.
Mom.
I was too naughty and playful.
I made you sick with anger.
How could that be?
Come and sit.
I'm not stopping you from playing.
I just don't want you to mess around.
If you like making things,
you should study it properly.
Whatever you do,
don't just do it half-heartedly.
Both studying and playing
require your full attention.
Understood?
By the way, Mom.
There's a rocket competition at the Youth Palace hobby class.
I heard the winner gets to attend a summer camp.
I will definitely study it well this time.
I'll surely bring back the championship.
I'll give it to you then.
You have to compete well.
If you have the guts, compete with me, Wu Wei,
once again.
Then tell Mom,
what is this about?
Didn't we agree
to throw it away?
Why are you still keeping it?
Xiaoba.
You're on your own from now on.
Don't!
Are you crazy?
Don't you know turtles hibernate?
It's almost frozen into turtle jelly.
How can you be so cruel?
My mom won't let me keep it.
She says playing with it saps my will.
Are you afraid your studies will be delayed?
And to think I used to envy you.
Okay.
How about this?
I'll raise this turtle for you.
Really?
Pinky swear.
Stamp.
Have you named this turtle?
His name is Xiaoba.
Lao Qi.
I'll raise Xiaoba for you,
as my apology to you.
Then we're good now.
By the way.
Let's join the rocket competition together.
Rocket competition?
Launch.
Launch successful! Launch successful!
Let's go. We're heading to Mars now.
Let's go!
Give me the oxygen mask.
Give it to me. Give it to me.
Mom!
Hello, Auntie.
Let's go to Earth.
Let me see.
You forgot the order again.
Wu Wei.
This part is very important.
Don't forget it in the finals.
Got it.
New max altitude record!
We won!
Team 3 of the Junior Group.
Won! First place in the qualifiers so far!
Mom.
I'm going to win the championship for you.
It's too late.
I'm leaving, Mom.
Slow down.
Don't be in such a rush.
My mom took me to the Math Olympiad.
But I'll definitely be back before the competition this afternoon.
You must wait for me.
Is Group 1 ready?
Get ready.
Is Group 2 ready?
Yes.
Don't miss any parts.
Get ready.
Students,
we're about to start.
Sir,
I have another teammate who hasn't arrived.
If you don't start assembling now, it will be too late.
Keep an eye on the time.
Mom,
I got second place this time.
Mom.
I got second place.
Xiaoqi,
second place is useless.
Everything is meaningless if you don't win the championship.
Do you understand?
Mom, wait.
I promised Wu Wei a rocket race.
It's starting soon.
I have to go now.
Now I know why you only got second place.
All you think about is playing.
How can you win the championship?
Participating teams, get ready at the launch area.
Wu Wei.
Why are you so late?
You chickened out.
We agreed to join the competition and win together.
Why are you so late?
Is winning the championship that important?
Only the championship is meaningful.
Is the championship more important than your friend?
The championship is.
Weiwei,
pack,
pack your things.
Go to the hospital to see your mom.
Mom, Weiwei.
Mom.
Weiwei, Mom.
Weiwei, Weiwei, let me go.
Weiwei, don't be like this.
I want my mom.
Weiwei, let me go.
Mom only hopes you can become
the person you want to be.
When you grow up,
do what you like to do.
I hope you are happy every single day.
Dad is back.
Where are you going this early?
For an interview.
You've been to so many interviews,
but I've never seen you so neat.
When you have time,
can you polish my shoes for me?
Dad, it's different.
I'm going to the Space City today,
for an interview at the Flight Control Center.
You step on the gas pedal,
and under your feet is asphalt.
I'm navigating the space.
My next step is towards
the sea of stars.
What's the big deal about space?
Don't look down on my gas pedal.
Morning, Sister Jia.
Morning.
Sorry.
Excuse me, sorry.
No, sorry.
Sorry.
Please hold this for me, thanks.
It's quite slippery here.
Are you here for the interview too?
It's just an interview.
Don't be so nervous.
Thanks.
It's starting soon. Hurry!
Front left.
Hello.
Is this the interview waiting area?
Yes.
You are also here for the interview?
I remember you.
Robotics Competition, Storm Doghead.
I watched your match.
It was a pity you lost, though.
No, let me correct you.
We didn't lose.
They cheated to win.
Our Aeronautics University was going for a three-peat.
Right.
Since it's fate that brought us here,
you should let me play with
your Storm Doghead sometime.
Rounding it up,
we can be considered brothers who shared a trench.
No problem.
Cai Bo'ao.
You can call me Caibao.
Wu Wei, from Aeronautics University.
You look younger than me.
Have you graduated with your master's degree?
No.
I have a Ph.D.
I got into the Junior Class at the University of Science and Technology at 14.
But compared to my classmates
who were 12 or 13,
I was a bit more mature.
Yeah.
What's this thick stack?
This?
It's a list of my published papers.
There are too many to carry,
so I just printed a catalog.
A catalog list?
A list.
What do you need the list for?
Wu Wei.
Thanks.
No worries.
Good luck.
Okay.
You may begin.
Hello, interviewers.
My name is Wu Wei.
I graduated from Aeronautics University,
majoring in Navigation, Guidance and Control at the School of Astronautics.
We've read your resume.
We want to know why you want to join Flight Control.
Influenced by my mom since childhood,
I wanted to be a Chinese astronaut.
But in high school,
because I failed the physical test,
I couldn't become one.
But I think even if I can't go to space,
being a star-herder is also quite cool.
You just said you were influenced by your mother.
Yes.
Does she like aerospace?
My mom is an aerospace worker.
She was in charge of logistics.
When I learned to read,
it all started with her aerospace magazines.
Then tell us your understanding of flight control.
I love aerospace and flight control.
In the vast space,
there are no road signs, nor are there directions.
If spacecraft are kites,
then we are the kite flyers.
Your grades are quite unbalanced.
A few subjects are okay,
but the others barely passed.
My major subject grades are very good.
Because I put all my time and energy
into my major subjects.
Are the other subjects not important then?
No.
I put a lot of energy
into my major and my specialty.
I also have some papers.
Although not many,
I really put my heart into researching them.
Young man,
relax.
Actually, your papers
have quite an advanced perspective.
They just lack data support
and practical demonstration.
Your papers haven't passed
or been published, right?
I tried to publish them,
but maybe they weren't complete enough.
With your grades and resume,
among today's interviewees,
you don't have an advantage.
Although the quality of my papers
might indeed not be good enough,
please believe me.
Believe in my passion for aerospace
and flight control.
Just give me a little time.
I can definitely
fix the flaws in my papers.
I believe in your passion,
and I know how hard your persistence has been.
But our principle today
is to select the best candidates.
So we will comprehensively consider
the advantages and qualifications of all interviewees.
Okay.
That's all for today.
The next candidate, Zhu Cuining.
Miss, the miss with short hair.
It's me,
Wu Wei.
Can I help you?
I wanted to ask about the interview.
Do I have a chance?
I can't tell you right now.
If you are selected,
you will be notified immediately.
Could you just tell me directly?
Please?
Our principle this time is to select the best candidates.
You don't have an advantage.
So there's no hope.
I'm really sorry.
But I really feel that
I love this flight control job,
and I think I'm very suitable for it.
I believe I can definitely shine
and contribute in flight control.
Please.
We value comprehensive ability more.
Can I get in the car now?
I'm sorry.
Is it because
I failed two courses?
Wu Wei.
Mr. Qin.
You forgot your resume.
Thank you.
Don't be discouraged.
Keep trying.
But there's no chance anymore.
You still have a long way to go.
As long as you have
a real aerospace dream here.
Come on.
Descendant of aerospace workers.
Xiaoqi's previous internship in flight control
was done under Mr. Qin.
Mr. Qin, Mr. Qiao.
Have some water.
Thank you.
Mr. Qiao, Mr. Qin.
Ziqi.
Your ideas for the robotics competition are very advanced.
Mr. Qin came specially to ask about your future plans.
Yes, Mr. Qiao.
I just feel that
everything must be planned
and arranged.
As long as we strictly follow the plan,
getting a PhD will be no problem.
You see this kid,
giving up such a good opportunity just like that.
It really makes me anxious.
Mr. Qin, Mr. Qiao,
you're just in time.
If Xiaoqi pursues a PhD in his major,
I don't want to.
Sorry for making you come all this way for nothing.
Xiaoqi.
Xiaoqi, Xiaoqi.
Don't worry, don't worry.
How about I talk to him alone?
Why do you really not want to get a PhD?
Absolutely not.
Then why not just come to our flight control?
This year, I want to organize potential newcomers
and form
a Star-Herding Team.
It's entirely based on young people's concepts.
The work tasks
will also be more flexible
and freer.
Don't you have internship experience?
Why don't you think about it?
Mr. Qin, stop trying to persuade me.
I really don't want to go.